[
    {
        "question": "Who scored the first century in the history of the Cricket World Cup?",
        "optionA": "Vivian Richards ",
        "optionB": "Clive Lloyd ",
        "optionC": "Sunil Gavaskar ",
        "optionD": "Dennis Amiss",
        "answer": "Dennis Amiss"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has won the most Cricket World Cups?",
        "optionA": "Australia",
        "optionB": "India",
        "optionC": "West Indies",
        "optionD": "Pakistan",
        "answer": "Australia "
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year was the first Cricket World Cup held? ",
        "optionA": "1967",
        "optionB": "1975",
        "optionC": "1983",
        "optionD": "1992",
        "answer": "1975"
    },
    {
        "question": " Who holds the record for the highest individual score in a single World Cup innings?",
        "optionA": "Sachin Tendulkar",
        "optionB": "Ricky Ponting",
        "optionC": "Martin Guptil",
        "optionD": "Chris Gayle",
        "answer": "Sachin Tendulkar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which team won the inaugural ICC Cricket World Cup in 1975?",
        "optionA": "Australia",
        "optionB": "West Indies",
        "optionC": "England",
        "optionD": "India",
        "answer": "West Indies"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which player has the most centuries in Cricket World Cup history? ",
        "optionA": "Sachin Tendulkar",
        "optionB": "Ricky Ponting",
        "optionC": "Rohit Sharma",
        "optionD": "Virat Kohli",
        "answer": "Rohit Sharma"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the highest team total in a Cricket World Cup match?",
        "optionA": "481/6",
        "optionB": "428/5",
        "optionC": "376/2",
        "optionD": "372/4",
        "answer": "428/5"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who captained India to victory in the 1983 Cricket World Cup?",
        "optionA": "Kapil Dev",
        "optionB": "Sunil Gavaskar",
        "optionC": "Ravi Shastri",
        "optionD": "Mohinder Amarnath",
        "answer": "Kapil Dev"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which player has taken the most wickets in Cricket World Cup history?",
        "optionA": "Wasim Akram",
        "optionB": "Glenn McGrath",
        "optionC": "Muttiah Muralitharan",
        "optionD": "Brett Lee",
        "answer": "Glenn McGrath"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who holds the record for the most dismissals by a wicketkeeper in Cricket World Cup history?",
        "optionA": "Adam Gilchrist",
        "optionB": "Mark Boucher",
        "optionC": "Kumar Sangakkara",
        "optionD": "MS Dhoni",
        "answer": "Kumar Sangakkara"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the highest run-scorer in the World Cup 2023?",
        "optionA": "Rachin Ravindra",
        "optionB": "Mohammad Rizwan",
        "optionC": "Rohit Sharma",
        "optionD": "Virat Kohli",
        "answer": "Rohit Sharma"
    },
    {
        "question": "WWhich team has the highest scores in the history of the World Cup?",
        "optionA": "India",
        "optionB": "New Zealand",
        "optionC": "Ausralia",
        "optionD": "South Africa",
        "answer": "South Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the top wicket-taking bowler in the two successive editions of the ODI World Cup?",
        "optionA": "Glen Mc Carth",
        "optionB": "Mitchell Starc",
        "optionC": "Shane Warne",
        "optionD": "Wasim Akram",
        "answer": "Mitchell Starc"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which team won three consecutive World Cups?",
        "optionA": "Australia",
        "optionB": "West Indies",
        "optionC": "India",
        "optionD": "England",
        "answer": "Australia "
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the First World Cup was held?",
        "optionA": "West Indies",
        "optionB": "England",
        "optionC": "Ausralia",
        "optionD": "South Africa",
        "answer": "England"
    }
]